<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chess on</title><link>https://ianonymous3000.github.io/Pr0f3ss0r-1nc0gn1t0/tags/chess/</link><description>Recent content in Chess on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://ianonymous3000.github.io/Pr0f3ss0r-1nc0gn1t0/tags/chess/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cyber Security Is a Game of Chess: Strategy, Anticipation, and the Battle of Wits</title><link>https://ianonymous3000.github.io/Pr0f3ss0r-1nc0gn1t0/blog/security/cyber-security-chess-strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ianonymous3000.github.io/Pr0f3ss0r-1nc0gn1t0/blog/security/cyber-security-chess-strategy/</guid><description>&lt;p>When the &lt;strong>NotPetya&lt;/strong> cyberattack struck in 2017, it spread across networks with the precision of a grandmaster executing a flawless chess strategy. Organizations worldwide were caught off-guard, leading to billions in damages. This watershed moment in cybersecurity history demonstrates how cyber security is much like a high-stakes game of chess—professionals must anticipate their opponent&amp;rsquo;s moves, develop robust strategies, and sometimes make sacrifices to protect their most valuable assets. The parallels between cyber security and chess are profound, offering valuable insights into how organizations can better defend themselves in an ever-evolving digital landscape.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lichess: The Open Source Revolution in Chess</title><link>https://ianonymous3000.github.io/Pr0f3ss0r-1nc0gn1t0/chess/lichess-foss-revolution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ianonymous3000.github.io/Pr0f3ss0r-1nc0gn1t0/chess/lichess-foss-revolution/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="lichess-how-the-open-source-community-is-revolutionizing-chess">Lichess: How the Open Source Community is Revolutionizing Chess&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;em>A deep dive into the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular open-source chess platform, its impact, and how you can be part of its future.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-chess-revolution">The Chess Revolution&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In 2010, a programmer named &lt;a href="https://lichess.org/@/thibault">Thibault Duplessis&lt;/a> had a simple yet powerful vision: create a chess platform that would be completely free, open-source, and accessible to everyone. Today, that vision has evolved into Lichess (pronounced &amp;ldquo;lee-chess&amp;rdquo;), a platform that serves millions of players daily and hosts billions of games annually. The name itself reflects its technical roots: &amp;ldquo;lila&amp;rdquo; = &lt;strong>li&lt;/strong>chess in Sca&lt;strong>la&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Ultimate Guide to Chess Movies &amp; Shows</title><link>https://ianonymous3000.github.io/Pr0f3ss0r-1nc0gn1t0/chess/chess-movies-shows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ianonymous3000.github.io/Pr0f3ss0r-1nc0gn1t0/chess/chess-movies-shows/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-ultimate-guide-to-chess-in-cinema-and-television">The Ultimate Guide to Chess in Cinema and Television&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Chess, the timeless game of strategy and intellect, has long fascinated filmmakers and audiences around the world. From intense tournament showdowns to metaphoric battles reflecting life&amp;rsquo;s complexities, chess has served as both a central theme and a powerful symbol in cinema and television. Here&amp;rsquo;s an updated and curated list of must-watch chess-themed movies and TV shows that capture the drama, intensity, and beauty of the royal game.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>