<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fundamentals on</title><link>https://ianonymous3000.github.io/Pr0f3ss0r-1nc0gn1t0/blog/fundamentals/</link><description>Recent content in Fundamentals on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://ianonymous3000.github.io/Pr0f3ss0r-1nc0gn1t0/blog/fundamentals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First Principles Thinking: From Foundational Truths to Revolutionary Solutions</title><link>https://ianonymous3000.github.io/Pr0f3ss0r-1nc0gn1t0/blog/fundamentals/first-principles-thinking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ianonymous3000.github.io/Pr0f3ss0r-1nc0gn1t0/blog/fundamentals/first-principles-thinking/</guid><description>&lt;p>When Elon Musk approached the challenge of building rockets at SpaceX, he didn&amp;rsquo;t accept the conventional wisdom that rockets must be expensive. Instead, he broke down the problem to its fundamentals: What are rockets made of? What makes them costly? This approach led SpaceX to revolutionize space travel economics, reducing launch costs by over 90%. This is the power of first principles thinking – the ability to strip away assumptions and rebuild solutions from foundational truths.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ikigai: Finding Your Purpose and Living a Fulfilled Life</title><link>https://ianonymous3000.github.io/Pr0f3ss0r-1nc0gn1t0/blog/fundamentals/ikigai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ianonymous3000.github.io/Pr0f3ss0r-1nc0gn1t0/blog/fundamentals/ikigai/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a world where many struggle to find meaning and purpose in their daily lives, the Japanese concept of &lt;strong>Ikigai&lt;/strong> offers a profound framework for discovering what truly makes life worth living. Originating from the Japanese words &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;iki&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> (life) and &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;gai&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> (worth), Ikigai represents the intersection of what you love, what you&amp;rsquo;re good at, what the world needs, and what you can be paid for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/76d2e94c-19ff-4d0b-970a-c64ef79efb59" alt="Modern Ikigai Concept Diagram">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The four overlapping elements of Ikigai showing the sweet spot where purpose is found&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>